The Brooklyn Democratic Party is suing Carmella Charrington.
Carmella is running for district leader, a party position that plays a role in selecting
judges, including the judge who sent Carmella to Rikers for protecting her home from deed
theft last week.
Carmella has been through a lot.
The day she was released from Rikers, cops tried to evict her from her family's home.
Councilmember Chiyose and others put their bodies on the line to stop that eviction.
One way that Carmella and her fellow organizer Omar Hardy are fighting deed theft is by
running for little-known positions in our local Democratic Party, called State Committee
or District Leader.
Electing Carmella and Omar would be a huge step towards ending deed theft and all the corruption
in our judicial system.
But our own Brooklyn Democratic Party is trying to kick them off the ballot.
Carmella and Omar teamed up with Ian Huntley and State Senator Jabari Brisport and collected
nearly three times the required number of signatures to get on the ballot.
The Board of Elections ruled that their signatures were valid.
But leaders of the Brooklyn Democratic Party sued Carmella and Omar, claiming that every
single one of their more than 1,300 petition signatures does not match.
What does this mean?
Do you remember how you signed your name when you got your first driver's license?
If I handed you a clipboard on the street on a cold day, could you reproduce that signature
perfectly?
If not, then our local party is saying your signature shouldn't count.
I spent all day at the Board of Elections yesterday.
Six Brooklyn district leaders and party chair, Rodnice Bashat-Hermelin, were there.
They say that every single signature on Carmella and Omar's petitions shouldn't count, because
it didn't look the same as the grainy file photos at the Board of Elections.
A 79-year-old voter's signature was invalidated, because it didn't match her perfect penmanship
when she signed her voter registration 46 years ago.
Party leaders even argued that Carmella, Omar, Ian, and Jabari's own signatures were invalid,
as well as those of all their campaign staff and volunteers.
I'll find out on Monday if my own signature will count.
The Court won't uphold many of these challenges—plenty of people wrote their signatures perfectly.
But by putting every signature under a magnifying glass, they're going to disqualify hundreds
of people who wanted to support these candidates, but were rushing to catch a train, or who can't
hold a pen as well as they used to.
Claiming does not match for every single signature is an abuse of our legal system and a huge waste
of time, but it might be enough to deny Carmella and Omar a shot at representing their community.
This weekend, we're reaching out to voters whose signatures were ruled does not match
yesterday.
If we can find them—hopefully they're at home—we'll ask them to sign an affidavit to
prove that it was really them.
I'll be back at the Board of Elections Monday with other volunteers, and we hope our party leaders
will do the right thing and drop these unfair objections.
But if they don't, we'll keep fighting for Carmella and Omar and all the other candidates
on the Brooklyn Can't Wait slate.
Then in June, we can elect a new majority for the Brooklyn Democratic Party—one that has
better things to do than stomp out our most promising candidates before they even get a
chance to run.